Sherwood Family Papers, 1654-1920, 1941 Ms 7
Fairfield Museum and History Center
Sherwood Family Papers, 1654-1920, 1941
Ms 7
Fairfield Museum and History Center
6.0 Linear feet (9 boxes,
Sherwood family
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Biographical/Historical note
This collection centers around descendants of Thomas Sherwood who settled in Fairfield, CT in 1648. Members of this family were land owners with large farms, tradesmen, sea captains and part owners of boats, general store owners and bankers. The Fairfield Museum and History Center hold extensive genealogy records of this family.
Scope and Contents note
This collection contains 9 boxes and 18 oversize items. The original part of the collection was processed in 1981 with additions made in the early 2000's.The number 1980.JL1 on some items indicates a Fairfield Historical Society Library accession number.
The original part of the collection makes up Boxes 1-VII and contains bills, business and personal correspondence, promissory notes, estate and probate papers, wills, estate bills, and distributions arranged alphabetically. Deeds, legal papers and writs are arranged by date. School notebooks, diaries, account books and journals are also in alphabetical order. Many of these items were donated by Royal Everts.
A series of Bradley, Mixter and Sherwood family papers (photocopies only) were added to the collection in 2004 and were processed and arranged differently than the original items. They are in Boxes VIII and IX and have the accession number L2002.3 and were donated by Laura Wilbur. This part of the collection contains Bradley, Mixter and Sherwood family letters, diaries, photographs and genealogy for Sherwood family members and allied Bradley and Mixter (Couch) families.
Of particular note is the correspondence and diary of Abigail Sherwood (1809-1862) daughter of William Sherwood. Abigail never married spending her entire life on the family's Hulls Farm Rd. farm. There is a letter in the series in which Abigail discussed the growing of Mulberry trees for the cultivation of silk worms to make silk material. Brother sea captain Aaron Moses Sherwood's letters to Abigail are in the series. Abigail's sister Elizabeth married David Bradley.
Bradley family; Couch family; Mixter family; Sherwood, Simon; Sherwood, Abigail Couch, 1782-1858; Sherwood, William, 1777-1844; William Sherwood and Sons.; Account books--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Bankers--Connecticut; Correspondence.; Deeds--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Diaries.; Fairfield (Conn.)--History; Farmers--Connecticut; Merchants--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Photographs.; Probate records--Connecticut--Fairfield; Real property--Connecticut--Fairfield County.; Receipts(financial records); School notebooks; Wills.; Writs--Connecticut.
- Box I, 24 folders
  Other Finding Aids note
  A detailed list of items in each folder can be found inside the box.
  - Bills and bills receipted, 1758-1883; Folder A; 39 items
  - Bills and bills receipted, 1758-1900; Folder B; 26 items
  - Bills and bills receipted to Simon and Mrs. Sherwood, 1869-1881; Folder C; 46 items
  - Bills and bills receipted to William Sherwood, 1803-1815; Folder D; 25 items
  - Bills and bills receipted to William Sherwood, 1819-1823; Folder E; 30 items
  - Bills and bills receipted to William Sherwood, 1824-1844; Folder F; 19 items
  - Bills and bills receipted to William Sherwood, 1845; Folder G; 22 items
  - Bills and bills receipted to William Sherwood, 1845-1846, n.d.; Folder H; 15 items
  - Miscellaneous and bills receipted, 1759-1883; Folder I; 34 items
  - Business correspondence, 1751-1901; Folder J; 24 items
  - Business correspondence, 1799-1880; Folder K; 21 items
  - Personal correspondence, 1790-1796; Folder L; 11 items
  - Personal correspondence, 1753-1796; Folder M; 25 items
  - Personal correspondence, 1817-1865; Folder N; 6 items
  - Deeds (Sherwood), 1697-1740; Folder O; 16 items
  - Deeds (Sherwood), 1741-1749; Folder P; 18 items
  - Deeds (Sherwood), 1750-1757; Folder Q; 18 items
  - Deeds (Sherwood), 1759-1769; Folder R; 20 items
  - Deeds, 1771-1778; Folder S; 17 items
  - Deeds, 1780-1794; Folder T; 17 items
  - Deeds, 1795-1803; Folder U; 18 items
  - Deeds, 1804-1812; Folder V; 18 items
  - Deeds, 1813-1817; Folder W; 24 items
  - Deeds, 1818-1821; Folder X; 17 items
- Box II, 27 folders
  A detailed list of the items in each folder can be found in the box.
  - Deeds, 1822-1841; Folder A; 20 items
  - Deeds, 1844-1857; Folder B`; 19 items
  - Deeds, 1859-1893; Folder C; 9 items
  - Deeds (photocopy), 1773; Folder D; 1 item
  - Estate and probate papers, 1753-1859; Folder E; 26 items
  - Estate and probate papers, 1772-1920; Folder F; 19 items
  - Estate and probate papers, 1818-1838; Folder G; 15 items
  - Estate and probate papers, 1735-1818; Folder H; 9 items
  - Estate and probate papers, 1768-1948; Folder I; 34 items
  - Accounts, 1757-1881; Folder J; 35 items
  - Account paid, 1755-1845; Folder K; 59 items
  - Orders, 1755-1844; Folder L; 27 items
  - Shipping and miscellaneous, 1758-1844; Folder M; 27 items
  - Tax lists, 1778-1842; Folder N; 9 items
  - Insurance papers of Eli Sherwood, 1880-1884; Folder O; 4 items
  - Legal papers, 1751-1831; Folder P; 41 items
  - Legal papers, 1740-1853; Folder Q; 32 items
  - Legal papers-Depositions, 1809-1830; Folder R; 7 items
  - Legal papers (Land and crop agreements, miscellaneous), 1654-1867; Folder S; 9 items
  - Promissory notes, 1785-1833; Folder T; 18 items
  - Promissory notes, 1740-1837; Folder U; 32 items
  - Writs, 1760-1816; Folder V; 19 items
  - Maps and military papers, 1800-1826; Folder W; 7 items
  - Miscellaneous material from William Sherwood journal, 1869-1883; Folder X; 37 items
  - Miscellany and genealogy from William Sherwood's journal, Folder Y; 93 items
  - Miscellany and genealogy, Folder Z; 10 items
  - School papers, 1756; Folder Z1; 5 items
- Box III: Sherwood Children School Notebooks, 1756-1888; 13 folders
  - Aaron Moses, 1827; Folder A
  - Abigail, 1806; Folder B
  - Albert, 1833-1834; Folder C
  - Cyrus, 1824-1825; Folder D
  - Cyrus, 1826; Folder E
  - Daniel, 1756, 1758; Folder F; 5 items
  - Edwin, 1818; Folder G
  - Justus, 1796; Folder H
  - Ralph, 1779; Folder I
  - Royal, 1887, 1888; Folder J; 2 items
  - Simon, 1812, 1813; Folder K; 2 items
  - Simon, 1816; Folder L
  - Unidentified, 1790; Folder M; 3 items
- Box IV: Diaries, 10 folders
  - Folder A
    - Aretta Sherwood, 1890, 1892; 2 items
    - Catherine B. Sherwood, 1859
  - Daniel Sherwood, 1756; Folder B
  - Daniel Sherwood (transcript), 1756; Folder C
  - Hull Sherwood, 1813, 1814; Folder D; 2 items
  - Hull Sherwood, 1815, 1816, 1812; Folder E; 3 items
  - Fabric cover of Hull Sherwood's diaries, Folder F
  - Miscellaneous diaries, 1864-1872; Folder G; 37 items
  - Folder G1
    - Edwin Sherwood (L87.Jan.1) with genealogy note, 1887, 1889; 2 items
    - unidentified, 1864, 1868, 1872; 3 items
    - loose papers from diaries, 32 items
  - William Sherwood's Book of Ancestry, Folder H
  - Loose papers from Folder H, Folder I
- Box V: William Lounsbury Sherwood Letterbooks, 2 folders
  - Letterbook, 1884-1885; Folder A
  - Letterbook re: family history research, 1886-1891; Folder B
- Box VI: Account Books and Journals, 1753-1892; 9 folders
  - Aaron Moses Sherwood diary, 1839-1841; Folder A
  - Albert Sherwood shipping book (1824, 1833) and Cyrus Sherwood Justice of the Peace (1831, 1837-1888), Folder B; 3 items
  - Daniel Sherwood student accounts, 1753-1757; Folder C
  - Levi Sherwood grocery store account, 1882, 1892; Folder D; 2 items
  - William Sherwood ship's log, 1801-1803; Folder E
  - William Sherwood (1812-1821) and Bradley Sherwood (1829-1845), Folder F; 2 items
  - William Sherwood contracts (1831-1838) and Sherwood and Gorhams (1791), Folder G; 3 items
  - Eli Sherwood, 1831-1871; Folder H
    General note
    This item is from accession number L86.Nov.3.
  - Anna W. Sherwood Morning and Evening Monitor, 1899; Folder I
- Box VII: Account Books, Journals, Miscellaneous, 1815-1824; 8 folders
  A more detailed description of some of the items can be found in the box.
  - William Sherwood and Sons, 1815-1826, 1817-1820; Folder A; 2 items
  - William Sherwood and Sons, 1818-1819; Folder B
  - William Sherwood and Sons, 1819-1820, 1819-1821; Folder C
  - William Sherwood and Sons, 1822; Folder D; 2 items
  - William Sherwood and Sons, 1822, 1822-1823, 1822-1824; Folder E; 3 items
  - unidentified, 1883, 1900-1910; Folder F; 2 items
  - Mary Sherwood's Sunday School attendance book, Folder G
  - L. F. Sherwood's Southport National Bank checkbook, 1901-1903; Folder H
- Box VIII: Bradley, Mixter and Sherwood photocopies, 24 folders
  - Sherwood genealogy, Folder A-1
  - Elizabeth Sherwood and David Bradley wheel chart, Folder A-2
  - Genealogy including proof of descent from Thephilous Eaton and journal of Louise Bishop, Folder A-3
  - Genealogy Wakeman, Burr and Chapman connections, Folder A-4
  - Genealogy Bradley, Folder A-5
  - Genealogy Elizabeth Bradley Mixter including DAR application, 1895; Folder A-6
  - Colonial Dames certificate Elizabeth Bradley Mixter, 1908; Folder A-7
  - Allied genealogies, Folder A-8
  - Couch genealogy including connection of Sherwood and Couch families, Folder A-9
  - Genealogy notes, Folder A-10
  - My Coat of Arms, Folder A-11
  - Helen M. Bradley's birth certificate, Folder A-12
  - Mary Couch Sherwood diary, 1833; Folder B-1
  - Mary Couch Sherwood diary, 1835-1861; Folder B-2
  - E. Bradley diary, ca. 1856; Folder B-3
  - Mary Sherwood Parnell diary (3rd marriage), 1867; Folder B-4
  - T. S. Bradley diary, ca. 1870; Folder B-5
  - Diary of Helen Bradley's trip to England, 1908-1909; Folder B-6
  - Photograph of William Sherwood and Abigail Couch Sherwood, Folder C-1
  - Large album and tintypes of Bradley family, Folder C-2
  - Photograph of Rev. Lewis Pennell and his wife Mary Sherwood Pennell, Folder C-3
  - Album of Bradley family pictures, the people who lived at 291 Pequot Ave., Southport, CT, Folder C-4
  - Couch family photographs, Folder C-5
  - Bradley and Mister photographs, Folder C-6
  - Unidentified photographs, Folder C-7
- Box IX: Bradley, Mixter and Sherwood photocopies, 33 folders
  - Abigail Sherwood correspondence, 1857-1860; Folder D-1
  - Letters from A. Sherwood of Hulls Farm, 1865; Folder D-2
  - Letters found in tan corduroy purse in Sherwood trunk, 1870-1890; Folder D-3
  - Dear Cousin Mary, 7 January 1863; Folder D-4
  - Helen Bradley Sherwood correspondence, 1941; Folder D-5
  - Thomas Bradley Sherwood to Elizabeth Bradley, 9 June 1870; Folder D-6
  - Elizabeth Sherwood (Mrs. David Bradley) correspondence, 1865; Folder D-7
  - Letters to Mrs. Mary Pennell from Sarah Bradley, 1865; Folder D-8
  - Letters of Mrs. Nellie Bradley of Southport, 1873-1875; Folder D-9
  - Copies of papers in Wilbur collection at Smithsonian Institution re: Abigail Sherwood, Folder E-1
  - Abigail Sherwood notebook, 1824; Folder E-2
  - Abigail Sherwood household properties with her sister, Elizabeth Bradley's share, 1862; Folder E-3
  - Invitation to Abigail Sherwood from managers of Yale College, 1824; Folder E-4
  - Wedding certificate of Elizabeth Bradley and Frank Mixter, 4 May 1877; Folder F-1
  - Golden wedding party of Mr. and Mrs. Frank Mixter, 4 May 1927; Folder F-2
  - Frank Mixter receipt to mother, 1900; Folder F-3
  - Obituary of Elizabeth Bradley Mixter, 16 August 1937; Folder F-4
  - Songs and ballads of the Revolution copied by C. S. Bradley, Folder G-1
  - Copy book of Betty Hyde, 1806; Folder G-3
  - Shipping correspondence, October 1808; Folder G-3
  - Isaac Jennings note for $30, 19 April 1859; Folder G-5
  - Sheffield Hall, New Haven, 1864; Folder G-5
  - David Bradley inventory of estate, 24 August 1866; Folder G-6
  - Estate of David Bradley to William Bradley, 30 April 1869; Folder G-7
  - Unidentified account book, 1878; Folder G-8
  - Invoice for teaspoons to A. C. Bradley, 12 December 1889; Folder G-9
  - Helen M. Bradley at Cornell University, 1904-1905; Folder G-10
  - "Scraps" property of F. S. Bradley, n.d.; Folder G-11
  - Newspaper clippings of devotional articles, n.d.; Folder G-12
  - Tan corduroy purse from Sherwood trunk, ca. 1830; Folder G-13
  - Linen baby garment from tan corduroy purse, ca. 1830; Folder G-14
- Oversize Account Books and Journals
  - Daniel Sherwood, 1708-1784, 1768-1808; Oversize Item A; 2 items
  - Levi F. Sherwood, 1839-1912; Oversize Item B
  - Levi F. Sherwood, 1888-1889; Oversize Item C
  - Simon Sherwood, 1850-1855; Oversize Item D
  - William Sherwood, 1825-1844; Oversize Item E
  - William Sherwood, 1830-1831; Oversize Item F
  - William Sherwood, 1836-1851; Oversize Item G
  - William Sherwood, 1856-1870; Oversize Item H
  - William Sherwood, 1861-1884; Oversize Item I
  - William Sherwood and Sons, 1804-1820; Oversize Item J
  - William Sherwood and Sons, 1804-1805, 1806-1807, 1815-1817; Oversize Item K; 3 items
  - William Sherwood and Sons, 1817-1823; Oversize Item L
  - William Sherwood and Sons, 1818-1819, 1820-1823; Oversize Item M; 2 items
  - William Sherwood and Sons, 1823-1825; Oversize Item N
  - William Sherwood and Sons, 1823-1826; Oversize Item O
  - William Sherwood and Sons, 1826-1830, 1831-1833; Oversize Item P; 2 items
  - Audio tape of William Couch Sherwood diary, March-December 1866; Oversize Item Q
  - Audiop tape of Emma Sherwood's diary, January-November 1880; Oversize Item R